<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: etc | Sandeep Raju]]></title>
  <link href="http://sandeepraju.in/blog/categories/etc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sandeepraju.in/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-18T01:26:29+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sandeepraju.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sandeep Raju]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@sandeepraju.in]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://sandeepraju.in/blog/2013/08/04/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-04T22:45:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sandeepraju.in/blog/2013/08/04/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Phew! Finally, a new look to my website! Hoping that this will last for a while without any more problems&hellip;</p>

<p>Ok, so a bit of intro to this site and then a bit on what i&rsquo;ll be doing on this site!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This site is powered by <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> and hosted on <a href="http://github.com">Github</a>. A few months back I started looking for a simple blogging platform. I started with Vanilla <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>, then moved on to <a href="http://ringce.com/hyde">Hyde</a> (for my love of python :P) and then finally to Octopress. Octopress is like Jekyll on steroids (at least that&rsquo;s what some of my friends told me ;)). After looking at the ease of setup and fair amount of documentation, I decided that Octopress was the thing to go with. If you are planning to use a static site generator, then I&rsquo;d highly recommend Octopress.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be writing on this blog almost on a weekly basis. But don&rsquo;t expect neat, tailor cut blog posts here. I&rsquo;ll just be using this space to note down some stuff as I learn new things everyday, so that I know where to search for if I need it anytime in the future :) But there is no harm in checking this space once in a while to discover something new ;)</p>

<p>Thats it for the intro post!</p>

<p>Hello World!</p>

<p>Happy coding :)</p>

<p>PS: I suck at grammar. Please correct me if I am wrong somewhere :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
