<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: linux | Sandeep Raju]]></title>
  <link href="http://sandeepraju.in/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sandeepraju.in/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-06T06:11:51+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sandeepraju.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sandeep Raju]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@sandeepraju.in]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Terminal Sharing Using Tmux]]></title>
    <link href="http://sandeepraju.in/blog/2013/08/17/terminal-sharing-using-tmux/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-17T22:10:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sandeepraju.in/blog/2013/08/17/terminal-sharing-using-tmux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I helped my friend setup <a href="http://vijaym.in">his octopress blog</a>. The problem was that, we were miles apart and interacting via chat turned out to be hard. What we needed was a shared terminal where both of us could see the commands entered by either of us. A quick google search showed me that this was possible easily using <a href="http://tmux.sourceforge.net/">tmux</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Simply said, tmux is a <em>terminal multiplexer</em>. What that means? Here is what the <a href="http://tmux.sourceforge.net/">official site</a> says&hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p>It lets you switch easily between several programs in one terminal, detach them (they keep running in the background) and reattach them to a different terminal. And do a lot more.</p></blockquote>

<p>Basically, its a better alternative to <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/screen/">screen</a> which I was already using for a while.</p>

<p>This is what I did to share <em>his</em> terminal with <em>me</em>,</p>

<ul>
<li>We installed tmux using the command <code>sudo apt-get install tmux</code> on both the systems.</li>
<li>Asked him to run the following commands on the terminal that <em>he</em> wants to share with <em>me</em>.</li>
</ul>


<p>```bash</p>

<h1>specify the name of the tmux socket with -S when creating it</h1>

<p>tmux -S /tmp/share</p>

<h1>chmod to allow me to access his socket</h1>

<p>chmod 777 /tmp/share
```</p>

<ul>
<li>Then, I logged into <em>his</em> system via SSH and ran the following command to access the terminal <em>he</em> is sharing with <em>me</em>.</li>
</ul>


<p>```bash</p>

<h1>now to connect to his shared terminal</h1>

<p>tmux -S /tmp/share attach
```</p>

<p>As simple as that!</p>

<p>Happy coding :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
